♪I scaled sheer cliffs for lingzhi,
then found you gathering moonlight♪
♪Two baskets of silver glow
rang out like stone against steel♪
♪You said to cure me of my hesitation♪
♪I'd need nine measures
of wind from the cliffs♪
♪And three measures of a heartbeat
that stops when our eyes meet♪
♪I caught your wrist and said♪
♪This condition is already beyond cure♪
=Hanyi Enters The Heart=
=Episode 22=
- Stop!
- Don't run!
Yungui!
You...
Finally
called me by my name.
I like hearing you call me that.
It's a shame that from now on,
I'll never hear it again.
What are you saying?
We still have so much left to say,
and so much left to do.
Are you going to leave me all alone?
I can't live without you.
If... If there is a next life,
would you
be willing
to... To marry me?
Why wait for another life?
In this life.
I'll marry you in this life.
Do you hear me?
Do...
Do you...
Do you really mean that?
I do. I really do.
Just hold on.
You're going to get better.
I'm begging you.
Please hold on.
Trust me.
You're definitely going to get better.
All right.
I heard it with my own ears.
She said she would marry you.
Now,
I can finally issue a decree
granting your marriage, can't I?
Your Majesty!
You two conspired to trick me.
Actually...
Actually, this was all my idea.
I wanted to know how you truly felt.
I want to marry you.
Li.
Do you truly wish to marry me?
♪I scaled sheer cliffs for lingzhi…♪
Why... Why are you still staring at me?
Hurry up and go after her!
As Your Majesty commands.
♪You said to cure me of my hesitation♪
First bow to Heaven and Earth.
♪And three measures of a heartbeat
that stops when our eyes meet♪
Second bow to the elders.
♪I caught your wrist and said♪
Husband and wife, bow to each other.
The ceremony is complete.
Assassins!
Protect His Majesty!
Watch out!
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty.
Li.
Take everyone to the rear courtyard.
Hurry!
Be careful.
- Go! This way!
- Go!
None of you are leaving.
Are you trying to rebel?
Enough talk!
Hurry, follow me!
Go!
Is everyone all right?
Your Majesty, hurry!
All right.
Go!
Watch out!
- Yungui!
Yungui!
The wound is highly poisonous.
Yungui.
Hold on.
I'll find a way to save you.
This time,
I'm afraid this really is goodbye.
Yungui.
I... I don't want you to die.
You can't die.
You have to hold on.
Do you hear me?
Take... Take my place
and protect His Majesty.
No.
I won't promise you that.
I can't.
You have to live.
You'll be all right.
Promise me.
Please?
Live well.
I...
Promise me.
I promise you.
I promise.
You...
Yungui!
Master!
Master, wake up!
Don't leave me all alone.
Master!
Yungui!
Yanzhi.
Dear.
What... What's wrong?
Dear!
Miss Shen.
Eunuch Li, this...
♪You stepped into the game yourself♪
♪Shielding me from hidden arrows♪
Hold on.
We have to save her.
Her water broke. The baby is coming.
Come on.
Come with me.
Miss Shen.
Come on.
It's all right.
Hold on.
Don't be afraid, Zheng Shu.
I'm here.
I'm right here.
Good.
Good. Very good.
Young Master Ju!
Hurry to the pharmacy in the west.
Get one liang of red ginseng,
four qian of donkey-hide gelatin,
three qian of charred angelica,
and two qian of notoginseng powder.
Boil three bowls of water
down to one over high heat.
Hurry.
All right.
Shu.
Hold on, Shu.
Hurry!
Shu.
Think of the baby.
Listen to me.
For the baby,
push.
Push!
You can do it.
Keep pushing.
Good.
(Hongyun Gate)
Yungui.
You asked me to protect His Majesty.
I swear to devote the rest of my life
to fulfilling what you entrusted to me.
Rest easy.
But there is one thing
I ask you to forgive me for defying you.
I will never forget you.
In this life or the next,
never.
Raise the coffin.
♪However distant the past,
however far the future♪
♪I stand here today♪
♪Unable to turn back,
with no shore in sight♪
(On the road ahead,)
(through countless storms,)
(I will face them all alone.)
♪You stepped into the game yourself♪
♪Shielding me from hidden arrows♪
(Three years later)
I want you to make a trip to Jiangnan.
(Liu's Apothecary)
Conduct a thorough investigation into Imperial Merchant Liu Xian.
That scoundrel exploits his supposed ties to the imperial family
to extort the people.
Wherever he goes,
he bleeds the people dry,
leaving widespread resentment
in his wake.
Until this criminal
is brought to justice,
I
cannot face the people of this realm.
Anything else?
Don't leave anything out.
Who is it?
♪Every step is hard,
every step fraught with danger♪
♪Every step is a battle with no retreat♪
♪As dawn approaches, those still asleep♪
♪Know nothing
of the bitter cold of the long night♪
♪If fate had not woven its threads
and spurred everything along♪
♪How could we witness life's upheavals
and the passing of time?♪
♪If this grand dream is destined to
be absurd, with no answer to be found♪
♪How I wish that when I wake,
I could still be by your side♪
♪However distant the past,
however far the future♪
♪I stand here today♪
♪Unable to turn back,
with no shore in sight♪
♪Between black and white, once a piece
is placed, there is no regret♪
♪You stepped into the game yourself♪
♪Shielding me from hidden arrows♪
♪Leaving me to a lifetime of solitude♪